( SLOW EERIE MUSIC )
( STRIDENT , DISCORDANT VIOLIN MUSIC )
( MUSIC FADING )
( MUSIC STOPPING ABRUPTLY )
( SLOW EERIE MUSIC )
( SLOW VIOLIN MUSIC )
( OMINOUS MUSIC )
( SNORING )
Mom ?
Hey , sweetie .
What are you doing up ? Come here . I don 't like my room .
No ?
That 's okay . You 're still getting used to it .
I can 't sleep either .
What are you looking at ?
Some old photos . You wanna see ?
D 'you know who that is ? No .
It 's me .
It doesn 't look like you . ( LAUGHTER )
I know . But that 's me .
It 's your mom .
I was a kid once , too , believe it or not .
You 're old now .
How old do you think I am ? Really old .
Oh .
Have a guess .
Probably at least , uh ... 21 .
( MOTHER LAUGHING )
Ah ... I wish you were right .
Show me a picture when Dad was a little kid ?
I wish I could , but I don 't think we have any .
He 's really hopeless at keeping photos .
Show me a picture of when I was a little kid .
You are a little kid .
You 're wonderful .
( BABY CRYING )
You certainly didn 't cry as much as your little sister .
But she 's up , so let 's go . Get some breakfast .
Billing department .
Let me play . No !
I wanna play ! Billing department .
Shhh-shhh-shhh . I need a bowl , Mom .
I don 't wanna play soon , I wanna play now .
No , no , no , no ! Here , here .
It 's too small . Well , just make it work .
( BABY CRYING )
Speak to an agent .
Speak to an agent ?
( BABY CRYING )
Ah ...
Oh , man . What ?
Every time I think I 've pulled you out -
ah ! You grow back in .
God . 'Morning , guys .
Speak to an agent ! I 'm the agent .
Yeah , hello , I would really like to keep the old number , if that 's possible .
Dude , don 't eat on the floor , Foster . But , I 'm ...
Can I have it by the end of the day , please ? Because ...
Yes ...
Okay . Thank you .
Foster , can you please get up off the floor ?
The cap 's loose .
Ah .
What is this ? That wax ?
We have no actual fruit ? We have plastic fruit ?
Tsk . Goddammit .
Honey , if you wanna look at my books , please don 't leave them all over the floor .
I didn 't touch your books . ( COUGHING )
Bye , buddy . See you , Dad .
Ah ... See you , buddy . You 're not gonna take the boys to school ?
I can 't today . Bye . Are you gonna pick them up ?
I can 't . I got a PTA meeting . I totally forgot .
Why didn 't you tell me ? ( BABY CRYING )
Oh , no , no , no , no . Don 't cry , don 't cry , don 't cry .
I 'll see you guys . Bye .
( SOFT MUSIC )
♪ Yeah I 'm looking west ♪
♪ Always been looking that way ♪
♪ I 'm gonna get it all happening ♪
♪ Just can 't do it today ♪
♪ Yeah I 'm looking west ♪
♪ Always been looking that way ♪
♪ I 'm gonna be somebody ♪
♪ I just can 't be her today ♪
♪ Ah ... ♪ ( BABY CRYING OVER MONITOR )
( BABY WAILING )
( QUIETING DOWN ) ( COUGHING )
Okay . ( STRANGE SOUND )
( STRANGE SOUND )
( LOUD CRACKING )
( SIGHING )
( STRANGE SOUND )
Hello ? Daddy !
Oh ... Hey , buddy . What 's going ... Oh , ho-ho-ho !
Hey . Whoa ! This is awesome !
Show it to your brother . Okay .
Show it to your brother . Come watch TV with me .
All right . Look at this , babe . Nice job .
Yeah , it 's getting there . No kidding .
Looks awesome . Thanks .
Whoa . ( COUPLE , IN TUM ) : Hi .
Pow . ( GRUNTING )
Pow .
( MAKING SHOOTING AND FIGHTING SOUNDS )
( CREAKING )
Have you seen my box of sheet music anywhere ?
Uh ... I dunno , babe .
I know we packed ' em .
No , I packed them . I know . I just ... I can 't find them .
I think the movers might 've put ' em in the , uh , in the dining room .
( BABY CRYING ) Come here , baby girl , come here .
Not in the dining room . I 've unpacked every single box
and ... it 's just vanished . Can 't find it .
Okay . But we 'll find ' em .
( BABY FUSSING ) We 'll find ' em .
( STRAINING )
( CREAKING )
( CRACKING )
( BABY LAUGHING )
( MOTHER LAUGHING SOFTLY ) ( BABY LAUGHING )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( CREAKING )
( BOY SCREAMING )
( DRAMATIC VIOLENT SOUND ) ( SCREAMING CONTINUES )
Dalton ! Honey , where are you ? !
( DRAMATIC SOUND )
Stay here . Foster , stay with your sister .
( SCREAMING ) Dalton ? !
( PARENTS ) : Dalton ! ( SCREAMING )
Hey ! What ?
Hey , hey . Come here . Hey ... ( WAILING )
What happened ? ! Did you fall off the ladder ?
D 'you fall down ? Are you okay ? Yeah ...
What are you doing climbing the ladder ? ! Honey ...
Ow ... Sorry . Are you ... are you okay ?
What hurts ? What hurts ? My leg .
All right , can you move it ? Can you move your leg ? Is that okay ?
Yeah ... Okay .
Oh , man , what happened to your head ?
Oh , gosh . Scraped it .
Okay . ( EXHALING HEAVILY )
Honey , you cannot come up here , okay ? Do not explore anymore .
It 's very dangerous , okay ? It 's off-limits now .
I 'm sorry , Mom . Okay , okay , it 's okay .
Can you stand on it ? I think so .
Be careful . I got you . C 'mere . What are you doing ?
You scared us , buddy . Just doing a little exploring ?
So no more exploring up there , okay ? Okay .
Yeah , you may be a superhero , buddy ,
but you 're not invincible .
You gotta be careful . All right ? Okay .
Yeah .
Good night , sweetie .
So were you putting boxes away upstairs or ?
Don 't , Josh .
I just hate feeling helpless . Sorry . We 'll figure out a way
to lock the door tomorrow . Good .
It 's ... dangerous , you know .
Maybe we should just put him on a child leash .
Stop at the pet store tomorrow .
I 'm sorry I was pissy when you got home from work today .
Oh ... didn 't notice . I was trying ...
to ... do some work today
and ... Cali woke up after a half-hour and ...
and she wouldn 't go back down and ...
I just didn 't get anything done .
I just want things to be different in this house .
Mm . I just had such a bad day .
I 'm scared nothing 's gonna change . It will , I promise you .
We just gotta give it time .
( SOFT MUSIC )
Thanks for let ... letting me take some time to work on my music .
Come on , I want you to do it .
I think I have a couple of good songs . I mean , not all of them , but I think ...
y 'know , there 's a few of them I can do something with .
I love all your songs . Shut up !
You do not . I do . Stop it .
Which one 's your favorite ?
Ooh ... ( WOMAN LAUGHING )
You should write a song about me . They 're all about you !
Yeah , like how cool I am . ( WOMAN LAUGHING )
♪ Ah he 's the coolest guy ... ♪ No , no , no , no ...
( MUFFLED SINGING ) No , no , no ! Shhh ... Qu-quiet .
♪ Big muscles ... ♪ Shhh .
( LAUGHING ) ( MUFFLED SINGING )
Shhh , you 'll wake up ... you 'll wake up the baby .
( MUFFLED SINGING ) Shhh .
( CLOCK TICKING )
( WATER DRIPPING )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
Foster , can you finish your eggs , please ? ( BABY CRYING )
Hey , Cali .
Can you go wake up Dalton , Josh ?
Yeah . ( BABY CRYING )
Hey , Mr. Sleepy Pants , get up .
Hey , sleepy pants ... you better get out of that bed
or your mother 's gonna kill us both .
Dalton , come on , buddy , gotta get ready for school .
Hey . Hey !
Dalton ?
Dalton .
Dalton . Dalton !
Dalton !
There is no brain damage ...
that we 've detected .
Technically , yes , he 's in a coma .
He doesn 't react to stimuli , he has no sleep-wake cycle ,
but there 's no brain trauma or infection . His scans are all normal .
To be honest , I 've never seen anything like it .
But he can 't just not wake up . I mean ...
There 's gotta be something ...
I 'm sorry .
Okay , so ... so what do we do ? Does he stay here ? Do we ...
Yes , we 'll conduct some further testing . It 's only been a couple of days .
It could take a little longer for ... ( BEEPING )
Excuse me a minute , I have to step out . I 'll be back in just a moment .
Dr. Sercarz , how long will the tests take ?
( SOFT MUSIC )
Okay , so what I 've done here is I 've inserted a nasogastric feeding tube .
To get the length of the tube that I 'm gonna need ,
I measure from the tip of the nose to the earlobe
and then down to the xiphoid process , which is here .
Then I usually mark that off with some tape .
And then we need to lubricate the end of the tube
that I 'm going to insert about four inches .
And then I just
slide it in like that . I have to make sure
that the end of the tube is curved
and that his head is a little bent , a little bent back .
And then we usually hold it in place with some surgical tape .
And that 's it .
( MUTED ) : If there 's any problems or any bleeding , just call me , okay ?
He 'll be fine ...
( SOFT MUSIC )
( PIANO NOTES )
( STATIC )
( INDISTINCT VOICE OVER BABY MONITOR ) ( STATIC )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( MALE VOICE ) : There 's nothing you can do .
There 's nothing you can do .
( STATIC )
( INDISTINCT VOICE OVER BABY MONITOR )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( WHISPERING )
( INDISTINCT VOICE OVER BABY MONITOR ) ( STATIC )
( LAUGHTER )
I need to get out and get away from here . I want it .
Give ' em all . Give ' em .
I want it . I want it !
Now ! ( BABY WAILING )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( BABY CRYING )
Oh , honey . Hey , hey .
It 's okay . ( BABY FUSSING )
It 's okay .
( FUSSING ) ( PANTING )
It 's okay . Okay .
What 's this ? An award .
That 's today 's date . Did you get this today ?
Honey , why didn 't you tell us ?
I know it 's hard right now , but ... things are gonna get better .
I promise .
I 'm gonna show this to your dad .
It 's fantastic .
I 'm scared , Mom .
Scared of what ?
Dalton .
Can I change rooms ?
Why would you wanna change rooms ?
I don 't like when he walks around at night .
( SLOW BEEPING )
( NOISE )
Something really weird happened to me today .
Huh . What ?
I heard this noise coming from Cali 's room .
It was on the baby monitor . It was like ... voices .
And I ran up here and had a look , but there was no one in there .
It was probably just interference .
Those things are always picking up somebody else 's signal .
Ah , I dunno . It sounded so clear . It was like this ... whispering ...
It scared the hell out of me .
I ... I was at the piano and I could hear it on the monitor
and I turned up the volume and ... ( BANGING )
What the hell is that ?
( BANGING ) Hold on .
Stay here .
Who is it ?
( JOSH WHISPERING ) : Jesus .
Hello ?
( BEEPING )
( BABY CRYING OVER MONITOR )
( CRYING ) ( DRAMATIC SOUND )
Oh , my God ! Josh ! Josh ! Josh , please , come into Cali 's room !
Someone 's in Cali 's room ! There 's someone there !
I saw somebody ! ( BABY WAILING )
He was standing right there ! He was standing right there !
( BABY CRYING )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( CRYING ) There 's nobody here .
I saw someone ! ( ALARM BLARING )
Ah . ( CRYING )
Okay , okay , take her , get Foster , go in Dalton 's room .
( WAILING )
( ALARM BLARING )
Foster ! What 's going on ? !
The alarm 's gone off .
( ALARM BLARING )
( ALARM SILENT )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( ALARM BLARING ) Goddammit .
( ALARM SILENT )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( BELL RINGING ) Thanks , guys .
See you tomorrow .
( EXHALING )
Hey , honey , it 's me . Um ... they just told me I 've got to , uh ,
I 'm gonna have to stay late tonight to , uh ... I gotta grade some tests
and , uh , it 's gonna be a while , so , um ...
you don 't have to wait up , okay ? Uh ...
I 'll be home soon as I can .
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( CRICKETS CHIRPING ) ( SOFT MUSIC )
( CAR ALARM BEEPING )
( SOFT MUSIC ) Did he respond
to , uh ... any of the new tests ?
No .
No , he didn 't . But we have to give it time .
I 've seen coma patients with a much longer inactivity time
suddenly start making noises .
He 's not in a coma .
They don 't know what to call it .
They don 't know what to do with him , so
they 've just given up .
I feel like the universe is just ...
trying to see how far I 'll bend
before I break .
Well , the universe picked a fight with the wrong chick .
It 's okay .
I got it .
Thank you .
You 're okay , honey .
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( DRAMATIC VIOLENT SOUND )
( DRAMATIC SOUND-SCAPE )
( CELLPHONE RINGING )
Josh , where are you ?
I need you to come home now . Please .
It 's 10 : 30 .
Mm-hmm .
You 've been coming home late every single night .
In all the years you 've worked at the school , you 've never had to do that .
Why , all of a sudden , are you staying back late ?
Y 'know , I don 't like it either . I was , uh ...
I was grading tests . I mean ...
What choice do I have ?
Gotta pay Dalton 's bills . Josh .
I 'm scared .
I 'm so scared and ...
I 'm scared . He 's my son , too .
You don 't understand . I 'm scared for Dalton .
I 'm scared of this house .
There 's something wrong with this place .
I 'm not imagining it . I can feel it . It 's ...
It 's like a sickness . Ever since we 've moved in ,
everything 's just ... gone wrong .
You think our house is haunted ?
I don 't think it , I know it .
Things move around in here by themselves .
I walk into the kitchen at night to get a drink , I can feel eyes on me ...
Um ... I can 't
be in there alone anymore .
I need you .
But ...
you 're never here .
Where are you ? I told you .
I ... was grading tests .
That 's not what I mean . You 're not ... here with me
in this situation . You 're just avoiding it .
Like everything stressful . Whether it 's this or a parking ticket ...
Oh , God , stop saying that , okay ? I don 't avoid stressful situations .
I 'm just dealing with it in my own fucking way .
( JOSH SIGHING )
Fine . Deal with this .
( DOOR SLAMMING CLOSED )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( THUNDER-LIKE SOUND-SCAPE )
( CRACKLING-LIKE SOUND )
( CRACKING )
( SCREAMING ) ( SCREAM ECHOING )
( PANTING )
Ah , God ...
( FOOTSTEPS )
Josh ?
( CREAKING ) Josh ? !
( DRAMATIC VIOLENT SOUND ) ( PANTING )
( SCREAMING ) ( DEMONIC SCREECHING )
( SCREAMING ) ( BABY CRYING )
( DRAMATIC VIOLENT SOUND ) ( SCREAMING )
Renai ? ! ( DRAMATIC VIOLENT SOUND )
( SCREAMING )
( GONG-LIKE SOUND ) ( BABY CRYING )
( RENAI SCREAMING ) Renai ? !
What ? What ? What ?
What is it ? There 's someone here !
( WAILING INCOHERENTLY )
He was right there , I swear ! ( BABY WAILING )
Don 't you dare not believe me ! ( BABY WAILING )
Please .
Please believe me .
I swear he was right there .
( BABY WAILING ) I do , I do . I do believe you .
I ... I just don 't know what you want me to do .
I wanna leave . Please , I wanna leave this house .
I can 't spend another night here .
Please . Please help me . Okay , okay , okay , okay ...
We 're going .
♪ ( MUSIC ) ♪
Lorraine , please , you shouldn 't be doing any of this . Just sit down .
I 'm perfectly capable of putting a few things away .
I did it for Josh his whole life . I know , but ... I feel terrible .
I think it 's , uh , you who should be sitting down ,
by the looks of it .
( SOFT EERIE MUSIC )
I can 't believe you got Josh to hold still for a photo .
Ah , what I can 't believe is that we are doing this all over again .
Ridiculous .
( SOFT EERIE MUSIC )
You must think I 'm crazy .
Nobody not me or anybody -
knows what you 're going through right now .
Whatever you have to do to get through it , do it .
And you don 't have to apologize for anything .
Thanks .
( SOFT MUSIC )
( NEEDLE SCRATCHING ON RECORD )
( UKULELE MUSIC )
♪ Tiptoe through the window ♪
♪ By the window ♪
♪ That is where I 'll be ♪
♪ Oh tiptoe through the tulips ♪
♪ With me ♪
♪ Oh ... ♪
♪ Tiptoe from the garden ♪
♪ By the garden of the willow tree ♪
♪ And tiptoe through the tulips ♪
♪ With me ♪
( UKULELE MUSIC ) ( FALSETTO VOICE STILL SINGING )
( NEEDLE SCRATCHING ON RECORD ) ( SILENCE )
( CREAKING )
( CHILD LAUGHING )
( LAUGHING )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( CREAKING )
( DRAMATIC PERCUSSIVE SOUND ) ( DOOR BANGING )
( SLOW BEEPING )
( CHILD GIGGLING )
Dalton ?
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( SUSPENSEFUL SOUND-SCAPE )
( DRAMATIC SOUND )
( DRAMATIC PERCUSSIVE SOUND ) ( RENAI SCREAMING , CHILD LAUGHING )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE ) OH , MY ...
( WHIMPERING )
( SOBBING ) ( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
... with faith , you know .
Ahem . Trust it , you know .
Hello . H ... Josh . Uh ...
It 's the first line of a joke , right ?
Guy comes home to find his wife with a priest ?
Uh , this is Liam Martin . He 's , uh ... Nice to meet you .
- Actually a very old friend of mine . Huh .
This is my husband , Josh .
What 's going on here ?
I should be going . Thank you so much .
Thank you so much for the tea .
This thing ...
from the other house ?
It 's followed us ... here . I saw
something today . I thought it was a little boy .
I followed it into Dalton 's room . But it wasn 't a child , it was ...
something else ...
So , what , you just ...
brought a priest in to get rid of it ?
I didn 't know what else to do , Josh .
Come on , Renai . When 's the last time
we went to church ?
What 's happening to Renai is real .
I 've seen it for myself .
I came today because last night I had a dream about this place .
I was in this house , but it was late at night ...
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
I was ... afraid .
I went into your bedroom , but you were both asleep .
( CREAKING )
I knew I was asleep in the dream , but ...
I could feel that ...
someone was awake
in the house . ( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
I went into Dalton 's room .
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( CREAKING )
There was something in there with him .
( SOFT DRAMATIC SOUND-SCAPE )
It was standing there in the comer .
( CREAKING )
( DRAMATIC SOUND-SCAPE )
I ... asked it :
" Who are you ? " and it said ...
it was a visitor .
I said , " What do you want ? "
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE ) ( CRACKLING )
It said , " Dalton . "
I can still hear that voice .
( CRACKLING ) ( DEMONIC ROARING )
( SCREAMING ) What ? ! What ? !
Oh ! It 's here !
( SCREAMING ) ( LOUD BANGING )
What the hell ?
( LOUD NOISE )
Ah ! ( BANGING )
( LOUD NOISE ) Ah !
Shhh . ( GRUNTING )
Ah !
( DRAMATIC PERCUSSIVE SOUND )
Jesus !
Oh , my God !
Okay . He 's okay . Please !
Please help him . Please .
I know someone who can help .
If you 're willing to ask .
I 'm Specs , this is Tucker .
I 'm Renai . Hi . Hi . You must be Josh .
Yeah . Hi .
That wasn 't psychic . Elise already told me your name , so ...
Where is Elise ? She sent us ahead
to do some preliminary tests .
Helps weed out the nut jobs .
Hmm .
What is that ? Uh , it 's a trifield meter .
It measures DC fields and the , uh ...
natural electromagnetic environment .
Yeah , sometimes , old wiring can leak into the atmosphere .
It causes hallucinations , changes in energy ...
It 's a little more important than that , but whatever .
Yeah , the tech stuff 's not really relevant to you guys anyway .
Uh , it 's all very relevant , actually .
( HUMMING SOUND )
( ELECTRONIC CRACKLING ) Pfft .
( GASPING ) What ?
Starfleet Series 1 .
Huh .
It 's hard to find .
Should 've kept it in its box . It 's ...
This device measures changes in UV light .
I make all this equipment myself , you know .
It 's impressive . Thanks .
It 's not that hard , if you know what you 're doing .
Mm-hmm . Yeah , that one 's basically a modified toy .
It 's , uh ...
I might need some time alone to concentrate .
( ELECTRONIC WHINE )
( ELECTRONIC CRACKLING )
( BEEPING )
( DRAMATIC PERCUSSIVE SOUND )
( DRAMATIC MUSIC )
This field is ... The body is made up of energy .
Where does that energy go when we die ? We can call Elise .
Now . ( KNOCKING )
Oh ! ( LAUGHING )
I wasn 't sure the doorbell was working . I 'm sorry .
That 's fine . Come on in . Oh , thank you .
Mrs. Rainier . No , Mrs. Rainier is my mother .
Just call me Elise . Oh .
I 'm Josh . I knew that .
You 've grown since I last saw you .
Since you last saw me ? Mm-hmm .
Your mother and I have been friends a long time .
Oh . Well , hello .
This is my wife , Renai . How do you do ?
Hi . Thank you for coming . Thank you for having me .
Can we get you anything , Elise ? Oh , no , I 'm fine , thank you so much .
We took trifield and EMF readings of the whole house . Uh , all the wiring ,
alarm clocks , radios , toasters , TV ,
the record player , fuse box . Nothing went off the charts
except for the , uh ... And the previous home ?
Um ... Tucker hadn 't monitored that yet . Y 'know what ? Don 't even sweat it .
I 'll make myself available . I 'll get on that this afternoon .
Yeah , but I ... I 'll have to come too , because who 's gonna operate the equipment ?
Well , strictly , I couldn 't do it without ...
Yeah , but I ...
Yeah . - Need to go see it .
That 's fine , gentlemen . I don 't think bad wiring
is the problem here .
Um , may I walk through the house ?
Sure . Of course . Thank you .
Your other children are with Lorraine , right ? Yeah , they are .
Ah , Stephen , do you have your sketchbook ? Uh , yes . Yes , I do .
Good , ' cause we 're gonna need it .
What do you need that for ?
Um , she tells me what she sees and I draw it .
It 's the most important part of her process . Uh , that 's debatable .
It 's not debatable . It is , but , uh , whatever .
Leave the light off .
Hey , Dalton .
You are a very handsome boy .
Your mom and dad are here , so don 't you worry .
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( CRACKLING )
What ?
( CRACKLING ) ( ELISE WHISPERING ) : Red ... red face .
Blood-red face .
( INDISTINCT WHISPERING )
Slow down . His feet are black ...
Slow down . I can 't slow down . His ...
What is it ? !
Oh , my God ... ( SPECS SKETCHING FURIOUSLY )
( INDISTINCT WHISPERING )
And pitch-black eyes like two dark holes .
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
He has hoofs for feet .
What ?
( INDISTINCT DESCRIPTION ) Elise ?
Hey , what is this ?
( DRAMATIC PERCUSSIVE SOUND )
( DISCORDANT PERCUSSIVE SOUND )
I 'm not sure if you 're ready to hear this yet ...
but , unfortunately , I can 't waste any time easing you into it .
I want you to know , this is what I believe -
and it may contradict a previous medical diagnosis ,
but ... you called me here
and I 'm taking that as an acceptance of my readings . Yes ?
Yeah . Go on .
Your son isn 't in a coma . Falling off a ladder
had nothing to do with this . His physical body 's here
but his spiritual body is not .
And the reason these disturbances ,
they followed you to a new home ...
is because , it 's not the house that 's haunted .
It 's your son .
I don 't understand .
Have you ever heard of astral projection ?
Um ... yes . It 's a ...
out-of-body experience or something ?
Well , I like to call them travelers .
You see , these are people with the ability
to leave their physical body
and to travel to different places in astral form .
Now , Dalton
he is a very accomplished astral projector .
He 's been doing it in his sleep
for a long time .
He has been since he was very young .
And he 's unafraid , because he thinks they 're dreams .
And it 's that very lack of fear that has led him to travel ...
too far .
And to become lost .
Lost ?
Lost where ?
In a place that I call " The Further . "
What does that mean ?
The Further is a world far beyond our own ,
yet it 's all around us .
A place without time as we know it .
It 's a dark realm filled with the tortured souls of the dead .
A place not meant for the living .
That 's where Dalton is .
And the problem is that with his astral body gone ,
he 's just left us with a physical body , an empty vessel .
And there are entities that know this because they can smell it .
That 's why they 're gathered around him .
Are these the things that I 've been seeing ?
Well ...
They 're all trying to get inside of his physical body
simply because they ... they crave life .
The chance to live again .
But there are other entities
who are malevolent
and have a more insidious agenda .
And then ... there is this :
A demon who seeks Dalton 's body
for one reason :
To cause pain to others .
He is so desperate to possess Dalton ,
he 's the closest of all the entities to getting inside of him .
What do you mean , the closest ?
Because these entities , they can 't just walk into the bodies
of the living anytime they please .
To cross over from their realm , it takes time , it takes energy .
But the longer that Dalton 's astral body
is kept away from his physical body ,
the weaker the link gets .
The easier it is to possess him .
Is there anything we can do to bring Dalton back ?
There 's something we could try .
It 's a little unorthodox .
But I would need your complete trust .
No , no , no . I 'm sorry . This has gone too far .
No , please , Josh , you said you would give her a chance .
Oh , I have given her a chance , honey , but I can 't have somebody come into our home
and telling us the reason our son is in a coma
is because his soul has floated off somewhere in another dimension .
We 're gonna bring her all the way here and not even consider what she 's saying ?
I did this to make sure you could feel at ease .
And if it helped , great . I 've listened to the dog-and-pony show .
I have seen the drawings .
But to bring Dalton into it ? No .
Well , why is our son still in a coma ? !
Why can 't the doctors tell us what is wrong with him ? !
How did the voice of reason become the bad guy here ?
Don 't you see , Renai ? You want to believe . Anybody would .
You don 't believe me ! You don 't believe me !
I moved houses for you .
What do you mean , I don 't believe you ?
I 'm on your side here .
But this ?
This is dangerous and exploitative .
You guys come into the home of a seriously ill child
and you make some ... tenuous connection between him
and the images my wife is seeing
and voilà . Tears validate your power ...
Thank you very much . That 'll be $ 600 , please .
Thank you for coming . Please . Please ...
Thank you . Uh , you know , no , I really understand .
Thank you for your hospitality . Good luck .
Oh , Jesus !
Sorry to waste your time .
Where are you , buddy ?
D-did you go somewhere ?
No .
No , you 're right here .
You are right here .
Can you hear me ?
I know you can hear me , but you gotta show me , okay , buddy ?
You gotta show me that you can hear me .
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
Ha ...
( SOFT MUSIC )
Okay .
What 's most important is that you realize
no two attempts are the same . I 'm gonna be completely honest with you
about the results . If there 's no dialogue established ,
I 'm gonna tell you .
These still cameras are rigged
to pick up any changes in the atmosphere ,
both electrical or temperature-wise .
Don 't be alarmed if they go off .
You 're gonna see a lot of confusing things , things you don 't understand ,
but do not question them and do not speak in any way .
I want you to know whatever I say when I 'm in tune is gonna be
at a very low volume ; you won 't hear any of it ,
but Stephen 's gonna write it down and he 's gonna repeat it for you . Okay ?
Dim the lights , please .
( SLOW BEEPING )
( DRONING )
( BREATHING )
We are calling out to you , Dalton .
( INDISTINCT WHISPERING )
Tell us you 're safe , tell us where you are .
Dalton .
Can you hear us ?
Answer us .
( SOFT WIND-LIKE SOUND )
( INDISTINCT WHISPERING )
( WHISPERING )
Who 's there ?
Dalton , it 's your mother and father .
( SOFT WIND-LIKE SOUND ) ( WHISPERING )
We 've been searching for you .
Where are you ?
( WHISPERING ) " I need help . "
" I can 't
see ... in here . "
Dalton . Dalton , you don 't need to see .
Follow my voice .
Follow my voice , Dalton .
( WHISPERING ) Dalton ...
Why aren 't you ... Why aren 't you talking anymore ?
Dalton .
( WHISPERING )
" If they ...
If they hear me , they 'll hurt me . "
Who will hurt you ?
Who will hurt you , Dalton ?
( WHISPERING )
" The man ... "
" ... with ...
" ... fire ... "
" ... on his face . "
( WHISPERING )
Dalton .
Dalton , can you find your way out ?
" There is ... no ... "
" ... way out . "
Follow my voice , Dalton .
Follow my voice .
" Be ... quiet .
They 'll ... hear you . "
They won 't hear me , Dalton . Follow my voice .
Follow my voice .
" They ... heard ...
" you .
" Oh , my God ...
" you , Mommy ...
" ... and Daddy . "
Help . Help .
" Help . Help .
" Help me . Help .
Help . Help ... "
Dalton ? ( SLOW BEEPING )
( SOFT WIND-LIKE SOUND )
( WHISPERING )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE ) ( WHISPERING )
" You ... bitch . "
( ELISE SCREAMING ) ( SPECS SCREAMING )
( STEADY BEEPING )
Dalton ?
Ah !
( RENAI WHIMPERING )
( RENAI YELPING ) Mommy ...
( GRUNTING ) Specs !
( RENAI SCREAMING )
( STRANGLED ROARING )
Leave this vessel !
( RENAI SCREAMING )
( SCREAMING ) Leave this vessel !
Leave this vessel !
Leave this body ! Tucker !
Turn on the lights !
Leave this body now !
( SOFT MUSIC )
Oh ! Dalton ?
Oh , son . Come here . Shhh .
He 's alive . He 's alive ?
He 's alive . Oh , God . Oh , Jesus . Oh , honey .
Oh , God .
Three cameras , around the clock .
We got nothing .
But I did find this on the video .
Take a look .
See that ?
I went through it , frame
by frame
by frame .
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE ) Oh , my God .
( CRACKLING )
( DOORBELL RINGING ) ( JOSH SIGHING )
Who 's that ? I 'll get it .
Hi , Lorraine .
Mom , what are you doing here ?
I asked your mother to come over . I called her immediately after the session .
Why ? There 's something we must talk about .
Lorraine , have a seat .
Go on , tell them .
Tell me what , Mom ?
The reason ...
I knew to call Elise in this situation , the reason I ... know her so well ...
is because I called her myself once , years ago .
To help you .
What are you talking about , Mom ? It 's no accident
that your son is a gifted traveler .
The ability was handed down to him . By his father .
Me ?
No , I don 't ... I don 't do ...
I can 't do that . You were about eight .
You suffered night terrors ,
these awful fits of ... pure fear .
You , uh , were terrified of an old woman
you said used to come visit you at night .
I dismissed your stories , I ...
( SIGHING ) ... I told you to grow up .
And then I saw her for myself .
At first I thought it was a camera problem .
And then I saw her again .
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
In each photo
... she got closer ( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
... and closer
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
... and closer to you .
Finally I was so frightened , I found Elise .
Do you remember ...
any of this , honey ? Do you ?
No , I ...
I don 't .
Suppressing your memory and your ability to astral project
was the only way to stop her from getting into you .
But in the back of your mind ,
you 're still afraid to have your picture taken ,
aren 't you ?
I kept those photos hidden from you ever since .
I advised Lorraine to hide them
to stop taking your picture ,
to just let you forget .
Who is she ? A parasite .
She befriended your astral body
and then drew you out into The Further just as Dalton has been drawn out .
I 'm so sorry , Josh .
I didn 't want to make you remember all this .
I do it for the sake of your son .
Your son is out there .
And you are the only one that can bring him back .
And with what we saw tonight , I would say
he doesn 't have much time left to wait for you .
Okay .
( SOFT MOURNFUL MUSIC )
You 've always been stronger than me .
You can do this .
I love you . I love you .
Please come back .
Remember why you 're traveling .
And keep one foot in this world .
Do not draw attention to yourself .
If they realize you are not one of them ,
they will come for your physical body in this world .
Ready ?
Yeah .
I don 't know what I 'm ready for .
Okay .
( TICKING )
Close your eyes , Josh . Take a deep breath
and relax .
With each breath ...
let the life around you fade into the background .
Just listen to the ticking of the metronome .
Focus on the spot in the center of your forehead .
The universe is deathless .
It 's deathless , because having no finite self ,
it stays infinite .
A sound man ,
by not advancing himself ,
stays the further ahead of himself .
It 's useless . I have no idea what I 'm doing .
( STRANGE HARSH SOUND-SCAPE )
( ELISE ) : Now you 're outside .
Let my voice be your guide .
Keep a steady stride .
Into The Further you go .
( THUNDERING SOUND )
( HEARTBEAT )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
Dalton .
( HEARTBEAT )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
He 's in .
( CREAKING )
Dalton !
( PERCUSSIVE SOUND )
Hello ?
Wait .
( INDISTINCT WHIMPERING )
Hello ?
( WOMAN CRYING )
( SOBBING )
Hello ?
I 'm looking for my son , Dalton .
( CHILD LAUGHING )
( CREAKING )
( DISTANT TUNE WHISTLING )
( WHISTLING A MERRY TUNE )
( SILENCE )
( DISCORDANT MUSIC )
( WHISTLING TUNE )
Dalton !
( WHISTLING CONTINUES ) Dalton !
( GUN COCKING )
Where 's my son ?
Tell me where my son is . Please !
( LOUD BANG ) ( GUN COCKING )
( LOUD BANG AND GUN COCKING )
( DISCORDANT MUSIC )
( MUSIC FADING )
( DOOR UNLATCHING AND CREAKING )
( DISCORDANT PERCUSSIVE SOUNDS )
( CREAKING )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( DISCORDANT MUSIC )
Uh !
( GRUNTING )
( GRUNTING SOFTLY ) What 's happening to him ? !
( PANTING )
( GRUNTING )
( GRUNTING FORCEFULLY )
Jesus .
Help him , Elise ! Please !
( STRUGGLING )
You 're stronger than they are , Josh .
You can beat them . You 're stronger . You are the one alive .
Get away from me !
Ah !
( PANTING )
( CLICKING AND CREAKING )
( STRANGE SOUND-SCAPE )
( SOFT EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
( CRYING )
( WHINING SOFTLY )
( JOSH PANTING )
Dalton ! Daddy ?
Oh , God ! Buddy ! Daddy ! Daddy !
Oh , my God . Oh , buddy . Daddy .
Oh , my God . Daddy ...
Oh , buddy . It 's okay . ( DALTON CRYING )
It 's okay , it 's okay , it 's okay . Oh , God . Daddy , look , I 'm chained .
Okay , okay , okay . Face me , buddy , face me .
C 'mere . We 'll get you out . We 'll get you out , buddy , okay ?
Daddy 's here .
Daddy 's here . ( PANTING )
What ?
What ? ♪ Tiptoe ♪
♪ Through the window By the window ♪
♪ That is where I 'll be ♪
♪ Come tiptoe ♪
♪ Through the tulips with me ♪
♪ Oh ... tiptoe ♪
♪ From the garden ♪
♪ By the garden ♪
♪ Of the willow tree ♪
♪ And tiptoe through the tulips ♪
♪ With me ♪
♪ Knee deep ♪
( DISTANT MUSIC CONTINUES ) Oh , God . Okay .
It 's okay . Listen to me . Look at me . None of this is real , okay ?
This is not real . Look at me . Look at my eyes , buddy .
None of this is real . We 're gonna go home , okay ?
You gotta help me . There 's one . We got it .
( CLANKING ) Oh , my God , Dad .
What ? He 's looking .
( DRAMATIC PERCUSSIVE SOUND )
( DISCORDANT MUSIC )
( SILENCE )
( DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )
( SNARLING )
( GRUNTING ) ( DISCORDANT SOUND )
Oh !
Baby . Stay here , baby . Come on , stay with us .
( DRAMATIC SOUND-SCAPE )
( GRUNTING )
( DRAMATIC MUSIC ) ( RUMBLING )
( DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )
Daddy !
( SNARLING )
( PANTING )
( DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )
( RUMBLING ) He 's made contact .
Grab the light ! ( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC )
( RUMBLING )
He found your son .
I know it . Well , then , wake him up , for God 's sake !
I can 't . He needs to find us .
( PANTING )
( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
I 'm scared , Dad .
( WHISPERING VOICE ) Ah !
( DALTON WHIMPERING )
( RUMBLING )
No ! Don 't !
Dad !
Please , Elise , do something !
( GLASS BREAKING )
Renai , you must call out to him .
Josh ! Josh , follow my voice !
Follow my voice , honey !
( EERIE SCREECHING ) Get away ! Get away !
Come back to us ! Follow my voice , Josh .
Daddy , listen , I think it 's Mommy !
Josh , come back , please . Follow my voice .
Josh , follow my voice .
Follow my voice , Josh .
( OTHER WORLDLY SCREAMING )
Follow my voice ! ( RUMBLING )
( RUMBLING FADING )
( SOFT RUMBLING )
( SILENCE )
( DRAMATIC SOUND )
There 's something in there ! In there ! Elise !
Stephen , Lorraine , go check on Dalton !
What ? ! Go check on Dalton !
What ? ! Go check on Dalton now !
What ? Okay .
( SPECS BREATHING HEAVILY )
Elise ... ( SLOW BEEPING )
( MAN SCREAMING ) ( JARRING DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )
( SOFT DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )
( DISEMBODIED SCREAMING )
They 're crossing over into our world .
( CREAKING )
( PERCUSSIVE SOUND ) ( DISEMBODIED SCREAMING )
( DISCORDANT SOUND ) Ah ...
( DISEMBODIED SCREAMING )
Elise ! Tucker ! Tucker !
( DISEMBODIED SCREAMING ) No !
You have to shine the light at Josh ! ( SCREAMING )
( DRAMATIC MUSIC )
( STRAINING ) Come on !
( GRUNTING )
( GRUMBLES INDISTINCTLY )
Shine the light on Josh ! On ...
( SCREAMING ) On Josh !
You 've got to call him back ! You have to call him back !
Josh ! Josh ! Josh , come back to us ! Josh , please !
( DISCORDANT MUSIC )
Josh ! Josh , come to , please !
Come on , Dad ! Come on ! He 's right behind us ! We have to go !
I 'm right behind you . Go .
( SILENCE )
You ?
( CREAKING )
( SNARLING )
( DRAMATIC DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )
( FADING )
( PERCUSSIVE SOUND ) ( DALTON SCREAMING )
( DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )
( FADING )
What do you want from me ? What do you want from me ?
I 'm not scared of you .
I 'm not scared of you anymore .
You can get away from me .
Get the hell away from me !
( SINISTER LAUGHTER ) Get away from me !
Get away from me !
Leave me alone !
Josh , please ! Please ! Please !
Come back ! Follow my voice !
Follow my voice , please , honey !
Josh , come back ! Come back to us ! Get the hell away from me !
Please , Josh , please ! Come back to us , please !
Follow my voice ! Follow my voice !
Please ! Please !
Josh ! Please !
Come back , please !
Leave me alone !
( GASPING )
Oh !
( DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )
( FADING INTO SOFT MUSIC )
( SOFT MUSIC )
I 've got Dalton ! He 's awake ! Oh , my boy ! He 's okay !
He 's okay ! Oh ! You did it , buddy .
You 're back ! You 're back !
( SOFT MUSIC )
( FADING )
Dude , I got some amazing shots . You were gonna write a book ?
And my photos are gonna be the main selling point .
Not the main selling point , but they 'll definitely be important .
They will be important .
A picture 's worth 1,000 words .
Yeah , but words are worth 1,000 words , too .
( SOFT MUSIC )
You 're really hungry , aren 't you ?
I 'm tired , too . You 're tired ?
No , you can 't be tired . You - Yes , I can .
No , you 've been asleep for far too long .
And you know what ? I 'm never letting you go to sleep again .
You showed me a new world .
No , I didn 't .
You 've been there before , remember .
Well , let 's hope I forget again .
Well , guess I don 't need these anymore .
( SOFT EERIE MUSIC )
What ?
Nothing .
I 'm gonna get rid of these .
All right . ( SIGHING )
Why did you do that ? ! ( EERIE SOUND-SCAPE )
Why would you do that to me when you know how I feel about that ? ! Why ? !
Ah ! Why ? ! Why ? ! Why ? !
Why ? ! Why ? !
No , you 're not tired .
In fact , you 're never going to sleep again . You have to stay awake
for the rest of your life . No .
Why ? ! Why ? ! Why ? !
Why ? !
( DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE ) Ah !
You bitch !
Can you watch him , Lorraine ? Sure .
Thanks .
Elise .
( DRAMATIC SOUND-SCAPE )
Josh !
Josh ! ( DRAMATIC SOUND-SCAPE )
Josh , where are you ? !
Josh !
Honey , please ! Where are you ? !
( DRAMATIC SOUND-SCAPE FADING )
Oh ... Oh , Jesus .
( WHIMPERING )
( DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )
Renai , I 'm right here .
( SILENCE )
( SOFT EERIE MUSIC )
( DISCORDANT SOUND-SCAPE )